songwriter.co.uk 2019-05-24

# International Songwriters Association (ISA) Songs And Songwriting • Cookies, Privacy & Rights

**PRIVACY POLICY**

It is the policy of the International Songwriters Association. hereinafter referred to either as International Songwriters Association or the ISA, to safeguard totally, the privacy of both its members, and of visitors to its website.

**THE ISA WEBSITE**

As mentioned above, the International Songwriters Association does not utilise cookies on its website.

Accordingly, you can visit the International Songwriters Association site on the web at any time without telling us who you are or revealing any information about yourself, including your location, hardware model, IP address, other unique device identifiers, operating system version, browser type and settings, such as language and available font settings, and settings of the device you use to access the Services etc. Neither do we track how often you visit, nor which pages you click on.

Again, the International Songwriters Association may embed content from, or link to, third-party websites and services, including social media platforms, that are outside of our control. While we encourage all sites to implement policies and practices that respect the privacy of our members, obviously, the ISA is not responsible for the practices or the content of anybody else's site, nor are we responsible for the security or privacy of any information collected by other websites or other services.

Your use of this site or your provision of personal or other information to use the ISA Services, indicates your acceptance of the above Policies.

**THE PRIVACY OF NON-MEMBERS**

The International Songwriters Association always tries to respond to queries from the general public (in other words non-members) who request advice or assistance, or who simply wish to comment on songwriting in general.

In the case of these casual visitors or non-members of the International Songwriters Association, the ISA does not seek, gather or store any information (including e-mail addresses, IP addresses, telephone numbers, or postal addresses).

Any information contained in, or which might be derived from such emails, telephone calls or letters as are sent to us by a non-member, is deleted once

(a) a reply has been sent, or 

(b) any request contained in that communication has been acted upon, unless there is a continuing need to retain it for the purposes of ongoing correspondence. (For example, if you send us a query, and we require further information from you in order to answer that query, we may hold the original email or letter until such time as the extra information can be added to it to enable us to respond.)

Accordingly, every communication from a non-member which requires a follow-up response from the ISA, should be accompanied on each separate occasion by an email or postal address or telephone number, as the ISA will not have automatically gathered or stored such information from a previous communication. 

**THE PRIVACY OF MEMBERS**

In the case of members of the International Songwriters Association, the ISA may receive and store the following information:

(a) Name of the member, where and as supplied by that member:

(b) Postal address of the member, where and as supplied by that member:

(c) Email address of the member, where and as supplied by that member:

(d) Email or postal communications where and as supplied by that member, including material forwarded to the International Songwriters Association for the purposes of examination, evaluation or copyright protection.

International Songwriters Association does not seek, gather or store any telephone or fax numbers, nor does it seek, gather or store any financial or banking information such as credit card or bank account details, nor does it seek, gather or store dates of birth, gender, or any other personal information whatsoever.

International Songwriters Association will only retain any information given to it by a member for as long as there is, in the opinion of International Songwriters Association, a continuing need to retain it.

Full details on what is stored in the case of an ISA member, can be found on our Privacy page.

Your use of this site or your provision of personal or other information to use the ISA Services, indicates your acceptance of the ISA Privacy Policy.

The International Songwriters Association may modify the above Policy from time to time. The ISA will notify these changes by posting changes here. Any changes to the above Policy will become effective when the updated policy is posted. Your use of the site or your provision of personal information to use the services following such changes, will indicate your acceptance of the revised Privacy Policy.

**SECURITY**

While International Songwriters Association does its best to protect all information sent to it, no security system is impenetrable, and International Songwriters Association cannot therefore ensure or warrant the security of its database, nor of such information you decide to transmit to the ISA via the internet. Accordingly you do so at your own risk.

If you do not accept the above disclaimer, then you must not transmit information to us.

**SECRECY OF INFORMATION**

No information whatsoever about any member or former member, including confirmation of membership or non-membership, will be disclosed by International Songwriters Association or shared with any third party whatsoever, except in the following circumstances:

(a) where it is necessary to protect the rights and property of International Songwriters Association as well as to comply with any applicable law or valid legal process. This includes, but is not limited to:

(b) requests by government or law enforcement agencies, where we may disclose any information we have in our possession to law enforcement or government officials in response to any inquiry or investigation or if in our sole discretion, we believe it is necessary or appropriate in connection with any investigation or activity that is or may be illegal or may expose the ISA, or you, or another ISA member, to legal liability:

(c) disclosures we are legally required or entitled to make under any enactment, rule of law or by the order of a court.

International Songwriters Association will not supply the e-mail, postal address or telephone number of any member to a third party, unless requested in writing by the aforesaid member to so do, or if we are compelled under any enactment, rule of law or by the order of a court.

**DISCLOSURE 0F INFORMATION**

Any person may request a copy of any information held on them by the International Songwriters Association, and can have such information corrected or updated at any stage.

Such requests should be made as follows:

(a) Email to internationalsongwriters@gmail.com

(b) Post to International Songwriters Association, PO Box 46, Limerick City, Ireland

(c) Phone to +353-61-228837

If you are not satisfied with the response of the ISA to your request, you may contact the Data Protection Commission.

Such contact should be made as follows:

(a) Email to info@dataprotection.ie

(b) Post to Data Protection Commission, Canal House, Station Road, Portarlington, R32 AP23 Co. Laois, Ireland

(c) Phone to (Lo-Call Number) 1890 252 231
